Anthony Deamer

66 Daphne Street, Grange, QLD 4051 | 0437 373 450 | Anthony.Deamer@hotmail.com

Career Objective

To expand my knowledge and experience in the software and wed development industry. I have worked in the trade and logistics industry for the last 7 years. Throughout that time I gained a lot of experience with working with computers and creating strong connections with cliental.

Education

YEAR 12 CERTIFICATE | 1999 | ALBANY CREEK STATE HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA OF INTERNATIONAL FREIGHT FORWARDING | 2016 | CBFCA CODING BOOTCAMP | 2021 | UNIVERSITY OF ADELAIDE- CURRENT

Skills & Abilities

COMPUTERS

- · Microsoft Office Excel, Word, Outlook
- · Airline Operating System HERMIES
- · Milman Operating System
- · Cyber Freight
- · Git-Hub
- · Visual Studio Code
- · Git Bash

COMMUNICATION

• It has been a requirement of all of the positions I have held to have excellent communication skills as well as building and maintaining good working relationships with suppliers, customers and colleagues

MANAGEMENT

• Whilst working with Toll Dnata I covered the team leader's position on a number of occasions. Motivating team members to consistently exceed expectation. There were from 5 to 10 people under me at one time per shift. As well as training staff and monitoring their progress at Wallace International.

Work History

IMPORT SEA/ RUNNER | WALLACE INTERNATIONAL | SEPTEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

Key Responsibilities included:

- Checking for documentation at each airline for inbound shipments.
- Registering shipments into the Cyber Freight system as operational jobs.
- Creating and confirming the correct charges on disbursement and final invoices for clients.
- Checking and updating transshipments and confirming of transshipment vessels.
- Communicating and booking inspections on behalf of particular clients with the Department of Agriculture and Water Resources.
- Lodging documents with quarantine.
- Paying out entries to get a clear status.
- Receiving ship spare parts and, organizing under-bond and deliveries to the Wharf.
- Booking cartage for Air freight, LCL and FCL shipments
- Keeping clients up to date with their shipments for deliveries.
- Quoting cartage for clients.
- Backing up every file/shipment onto a hard drive.
- Confirming with clients of correct documentation for entries.
- Communicating with different Freight Forwarders and Shipping lines for Arrival notices, Tax Invoices, Delivery Orders and Outturn Reports.

•

OPERATIONS CLERK - RUNNER | CUSTOMS AND FORWARDING SERVICES | OCTOBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2020

Key Responsibilities included:

- Checking for documentation at each airline for inbound shipments.
- Registering shipments into the Cyber Freight system as operational jobs.
- Creating and confirming the correct charges on disbursement and final invoices for clients.
- Checking and updating transshipments and confirming of transshipment vessels.
- Communicating and booking inspections on behalf of particular clients with the Department of Agriculture and Water Resources.
- Lodging documents with quarantine.
- Paying out entries to get a clear status.
- Receiving ship spare parts and, organizing under-bond and deliveries to the Wharf.
- Booking cartage for Air freight, LCL and FCL shipments
- Keeping clients up to date with their shipments for deliveries.
- Quoting cartage for clients.
- Backing up every file/shipment onto a hard drive.
- Confirming with clients of correct documentation for entries.
- Communicating with different Freight Forwarders and Shipping lines for Arrival notices, Tax Invoices, Delivery Orders and Outturn Reports.

BAGGAGE HANDLER - RAMP SERVICES AND AIR-CARGO AGENT | TOLL DNATA | JANUARY 2012 - JUNE 2014

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Supporting and covering the team leader position
- · Baggage handling
- · Heavy machinery operations
- · Two way radio operation
- · Processing cargo documents
- Operating the Hermies Airline computer system which included data capturing all of the Air Way Bills (AWB); requesting under-bonds for cargo; checking fees and correcting if necessary; creating flights for unexpected inbound flights; preparing inbound flights to be ready for when flights arrived and receiving inbound documents in the system.
- · Ensure cargo had customs clearance
- · Operating the Emerites Sky Cargo computer system print AWB's for inbound flights
- · Data entry on the Virgin Australia WABlink computer system. This was to ensure that the load control would be able to load the plan safely
- · General Customer service
- · Receiving import and export cargo
- · Follow company policies and procedures to ensure safe work practice

SALES ASSISTANT | HARRY BROWNS LIQUOR STORE | DECEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Customer Service
- Support management by restocking merchandise and maintaining excellent customer service standards
- · Managed cash register credit card, cash and return transactions ensuring register balanced.
- · Monthly Stock take
- · Manual handling

SIGN WRITER ASSISTANT | PLANET WRAP SIGN WRITING | JANUARY 2010 - DECEMBER 2010

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Customer Service
- · Assisting with the design, making, painting and installation of signs for a variety of customers
- · Ensure that work was completed to tight deadlines
- · Working and learning practical skills on the job

REFEREES

David Gray – Operations Customs and Forwarding Services Mobile -0424 505 435

Wayne Anderson- Office Team Leader Toll Dnata Cargo Service Mobile: 0420 505103

Additional references available on request.